Every year brings a great movie. Every decade a great movie musical!
Bugsy Malone is a drama, action, comedy film directed by Alan Parker.
New York, 1929, a war rages between two rival gangsters, Fat Sam and Dandy Dan.
Dan is in possession of a new and deadly weapon, the dreaded "splurge gun".
As the custard pies fly, Bugsy Malone, an all-round nice guy, falls
for Blousey Brown, a singer at Fat Sam's speakeasy.
His designs on her are disrupted by the seductive
songstress Tallulah who wants Bugsy for herself.
Bugsy Malone, played by Scott Baio.
Tallulah, played by Jodie Foster.
Blousey, played by Florrie Dugger.
Fat Sam, played by John Cassisi.
Dandy Dan, played by Martin Lev.
Leroy Smith, played by Paul Murphy.
Bugsy Malone is a 1976 gangster musical comedy film written and directed
by Alan Parker (in his feature film directorial debut).
A co-production of the United States and United Kingdom, it features an ensemble cast, comprising only child and
teenage actors playing adult roles, with Jodie Foster, Scott Baio, and John Cassisi in major roles.
The film tells the story of the rise of "Bugsy Malone" and the
battle for power between "Fat Sam" and "Dandy Dan".
Set in New York City, it is a gangster movie spoof, with machine guns
that fire gobs of whipped cream instead of bullets.
The film is based loosely on events in New York and Chicago during Prohibition era,
specifically the exploits of real-life gangsters such as Al Capone and Bugs Moran.
Parker lightened the subject matter considerably for the children's
market and the film received a G rating in the U.S.
Bugsy Malone premiered at the 1976 Cannes Film Festival,
where it competed for the Palme d'Or.
It was theatrically released in the United Kingdom on July 23, 1976, by Fox-Rank
Distributors, and in the United States by Paramount Pictures on September 15.
Although a commercial success in the UK, it was
not a financial success overseas.
The film received critical acclaim, with praise drawn for Parker's screenplay and
direction, its musical numbers, unique narrative and the performances of the cast.
Over the years, Bugsy Malone has been cited amongst
the greatest films in cinema history.
In 2008, Empire ranked it 353rd on their list of
500 greatest movies of all time.
The film received eight nominations at the 30th British Academy Film Awards, including Best Film, and won three: Best
Supporting Actress and Most Promising Newcomer to Leading Film Roles for Foster and Best Screenplay for Parker.
The film also received three nominations at the 34th Golden Globe
Awards including Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of new york city,
prohibition era, gangster, musical, 1920s.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.